Guide to the New York University Library Accession Books MC.258
New York University Archives
New York University Library Accession Books
1830-1967
New York University Archives
New York University. Library Division
MC.258
9.6 Linear Feet in 59 boxes
The collection contains ledgers recording the accession of books, periodicals, manuscripts, and other items by various New York University libraries between 1830 and 1967. Some ledgers contain catalogs of authors, theses, and bill payments.
Appraisal
In September 2018, the De La Garde Library accession book was deaccessioned from the University Archives and transferred to the Fales Library and Special Collections.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chonologically.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains ledgers recording the accession of books, periodicals, manuscripts, and other items by various New York University libraries between 1830 and 1967. Some ledgers contain catalogs of authors, theses, and bill payments.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials.
- Library Accession Books inventory
  - Library Accession Book, circa 1830s (Box 2)
  - Library Accession Book, University Library Catalog, 1830-1840 (Box 3)
  - Library Accession Book, 1835 (Box 1)
  - Library Accession Book, University Library Donations Ledger, 1835-1892 (Box 51)
  - Library Accession Book, 1896-1901 (Box 4)
  - Library Accession Book, 1898-1899 (Box 5)
  - Library Accession Book, Catalogue of Subjects, circa 19th Century (Box 55)
  - Library Accession Book, circa Early 20th Century (Box 6)
  - Library Accession Book, circa 1900s-1930s (Box 7)
  - Library Accession Book, Bachelor of Science Theses, circa 1900-1930 (Box 54)
  - Library Accession Book, Register of Borrowers, 1904 (Box 52)
  - Library Accession Book, 1900-1909 (Box 8)
  - Library Accession Book, 1900-1920 (Box 9)
  - Library Accession Book, Library Order Book, 1906-1915 (Box 8)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 3), circa 1850-1861 (Box 10)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 4), 1896-1898 (Box 11)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 5), 1898-1899 (Box 12)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 6), 1898-1899 (Box 13)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 7), 1899-1901 (Box 14)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 8), 1901-1902 (Box 15)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 9), 1902-1903 (Box 16)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 10), 1903 (Box 17)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 11), 1903-1906 (Box 18)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 12), 1906-1908 (Box 19)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 13), 1908-1912 (Box 20)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 14), 1912-1914 (Box 21)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 15), 1914-1915 (Box 22)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 16), 1915-1918 (Box 23)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 17), 1918-1921 (Box 24)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 18), 1921-1922 (Box 25)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 19), 1922-1923 (Box 26)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 20), 1923-1925 (Box 27)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 21), 1925-1926 (Box 28)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 22), 1926-1927 (Box 29)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 23), 1927-1929 (Box 30)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 24), 1929 (Box 31)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 25), 1929-1930 (Box 32)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 26), 1930-1931 (Box 33)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 27), 1931-1933 (Box 34)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 28), 1933-1934 (Box 35)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 29), 1934-1935 (Box 36)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 30), 1935-1936 (Box 37)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 31), 1936-1937 (Box 38)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 32), 1937-1938 (Box 39)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 33), 1938-1940 (Box 40)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 34), 1940-1941 (Box 41)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 35), 1941-1943 (Box 42)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 36), 1943-1945 (Box 43)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 37), 1945-1947 (Box 44)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 38), 1947-1948 (Box 45)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 39), 1948-1950 (Box 46)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 40), 1950-1951 (Box 47)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 41), 1951-1953 (Box 48)
  - Library Accession Book (Volume 42), 1953 (Box 49)
  - Library Accession Book, Ledger of Items Added, Deleted, Lost, 1945-1957 (Box 50)
  - Library Accession Book: Catalogue of Books, Undated (Box 53)
  - Library Accession Book: Catalogue of Books Systematically Arranged, Undated (Box 56)
  - Library Accession Book: Catalogue of Authors and Catalogue of Subjects, Undated (Box 57)
  - Library Accession Book: Gould Memorial Library (August), 1967 (Box 8)
  - Library Accession Book: Gould Memorial Library (September), 1967 (Box 8)
  - Library Accession Book: Gould Memorial Library (October), 1967 (Box 8)
  - Library Accession Book: University Heights Library, Bills sent for payment, 1931-1943 (Box 58)
  - Library Accession Book: University Heights Library, Bills sent for payment, 1919-1931 (Box 59)